Guide to The Billie Jean King Collection 1901-2019 (bulk, 1940-2019) MS 3147
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. (RESTRICTED) Audiovisual and digital formats, 1973-2018; 1 Linear feet
  - Subseries IX.C. Optical disks [CDs and DVDs], 2001-2018
    - Elton John "The Diving Board" - CD, 2013 (Offsite-box 52)
      Includes handwritten note on CD sleeve from Elton John to BJK and Ilana Kloss.
    - Lee Holley Celebration of Life - DVD, 2018 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Battle of the Sexes - DVD, undated (Offsite-box 52)
  - Subseries IX.D. USB flash drives, 2016
    - Ellis Island Family Heritage Awards, 2016 (Offsite-box 52)
      Includes USB drive and accompanying letter from The Statue of Liberty-Ellis Island Foundation, Inc.
  - Subseries IX.E. Digital Files
    - Billie Jean King and Michelle Obama celebrate the 50th anniversary of equal pay for men and women at the US Open, August 2023 (Digital-folder 1)
      This digital file (MP4) is a video of Billie Jean King and Michelle Obama at the US Open in 2023, celebrating the 50th anniversary of equal pay for men and women. It is 12 minutes long and can be made available upon request by contacting manuscripts@nyhistory.org.
- Series X. Artifacts and memorabilia, 1940-2019; 4 Linear feet in 3 record cartons, 1 flat box, and 1 oversize long box
  Series X. includes all objects in the collection, including photographs that have been selected to remain in original framed condition. Items include plaques, pins, buttons, and clothing. Items date from 1940-2019.
  - Mildred Jerman Hairdresser and Cosmetician license, 1940-1941 (Offsite-box 54)
  - Framed photographs, 1940-2005 (Offsite-box 54)
    These photographs were determined by the manuscripts curator and conservation department to remain in their original frames to retain context and/or due to unique engraving of the frame. Photographs include BJK family photos and event photos. There are 12 frames in total.
  - Felt varsity letters, circa 1950s (Offsite-box 55)
    Black and white "L" varsity letter and black and orange "H" varsity letter.
  - Framed one dollar bill, 1970 (Offsite-box 54)
    This framed dollar bill is possibly the dollar that BJK received upon signing the original one dollar contract with Gladys Heldman at the Houston Racquet Club in September 1970 as part of the "Original 9."
  - BJK Tennis Center Long Beach visor, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 53)
    Two identical white plastic visors with the text "Billie Jean King Tennis Center Long Beach, CA."
  - Virginia Slims World Championship Series sweatshirt, circa 1970s (Offsite-box 53)
  - Virginia Slims Circuit buttons, circa 1970s (Offsite-box 55)
    Three buttons with text "Virginia Slims Circuit You've come a long way, baby" and Virginia Slims character.
  - Virginia Slims character gold pins and pendants, circa 1970s (Offsite-box 55)
    Thirty-seven gold pins and 14 gold pendants in the design of the Virginia Slims character.
  - Billie Jean is #1 buttons, circa 1970s-1980s (Offsite-box 55)
    Six buttons with text "Billie Jean is #1."
  - Philadelphia Freedoms WT East Champions mounted and framed photo, 1974 (Offsite-box 56)
  - womenSports first issue cover plaque, 1974 June (Offsite-box 65, Item 2)
    Wooden plaque with plate of the inaugural cover of womenSports magazine with photo of BJK. Engraved caption reads "This represents the key plate used to print the cover of the first issue of womenSports by R.R. Donnelley & Sons Company Glasgow, Kentucky. Presented to Jim Jorgensen."
  - New York Apples World TeamTennis buttons, circa 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 55)
    Six white buttons with text "new york apples world team tennis champions."
  - Tennis Magazine recognition plaque, 1985 (Offsite-box 56)
    Engraved plaque encased in acrylic reading "tennis magazine Salutes BJK as one of the 20 top players in the game over the past 20 years 1965-1985."
  - Domino's Pizza box top, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 59, Folder 5)
    Domino's Pizza box top with signatures from Chris Evert, BJK, Martina Navratilova, and Pam Shriver. Domino's Pizza was the sponsor of the TeamTennis league from 1985-1991.
  - United States Sports Academy award wooden plaque, 1989 (Offsite-box 26)
  - Mounted photo plaque of BJK, Chris Evert, Martina Navratilova, and Pam Shriver, circa 1990s (Offsite-box 59)
  - BJK World TeamTennis bobblehead, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 53)
  - Engraved granite portrait of BJK and Ilana Kloss, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 53)
  - Barbara S. Wynne Tennis Center keychain, 2003 (Offsite-box 55)
  - BJK 60th birthday invitation framed, 2003 November 9 (Offsite-box 54)
  - BJK and Ilana Kloss event credentials (5 of 9 envelopes), 2000s (Offsite-box 51)
    Credential badges for BJK and Ilana Kloss for various events, including the Australian Open, BNP Paribas WTS, French Open, US Open, Wimbledon, Democratic National Conventions, and concerts. Badges are grouped by event and stored in envelopes.
  - BJK and Ilana Kloss event credentials (4 of 9 envelopes), 2000s (Offsite-box 53)
  - Fed Cup sign, 2003 (Offsite-box 56)
    Foam board sign reading "Sportsmen's Tennis Club and Bud Collins welcomes BJK and Fed Cup '03 to Boston."
  - Kraft Nabisco Championship Tennis Pro-Am photo plaque, 2004 (Offsite-box 56)
    Features photos of Ilana Kloss and other participants.
  - Alice Paul jail door souvenir, circa 2005 (Offsite-box 55)
    Alice Paul jail door pin and pendant produced as a souvenir by the National Woman's Party for the Sewall-Belmont House & Museum, now known as the Belmont-Paul Women's Equality National Monument.
  - GLBT Historical Society Walker award, 2006 (Offsite-box 66, Item 1)
    Framed photograph and caption awarded to BJK.
  - BJK quote handbag, 2008 (Offsite-box 54)
    Tote bag and accompanying note to BJK. Tote bag reads "Champions keep playing until they get it right -BJK" and was created for the athletes attending Women's Sports Foundation's event The Billies 2008.
  - Hillary for President sign, 2008 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 7)
    Hillary for President sign from HRC's 2008 campaign. Signed to BJK by HRC and Bill Clinton.
  - New York Liberty Outdoor Classic at Arthur Ashe Stadium t-shirt, 2008 (Offsite-box 53)
  - Starkey Hearing Foundation Distinguished Humanitarian Award, 2008 (Offsite-box 56)
    Circular platter of cut glass made by Tiffany & Co. presented to BJK by the Starkey Hearing Foundation. Stored in original Tiffany & Co. box.
  - United States Department of State Certificate of Recognition, 2012 June 21 (Offsite-box 65, Item 1)
    Certificate mounted on wood awarded to BJK. Text on certificate reads "In appreciation of your outstanding contributions to the U.S. Department of State's Council to Empower Women and Girls through Sports. Your public service to elevate the global conversation on advancing the rights of women and girls is inspiring and your support is truly appreciated." Includes inserted letter from Ann Stock, Assistant Secretary, Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs.
  - Celebrating 40 years of WTA medal, 2013 (Offsite-box 55)
  - USTA/ Midwest Section Hall of Fame plaque, 2013 (Offsite-box 56)
  - Mylan WTT BJK and Ilana Kloss nameplates, circa 2013-2016 (Offsite-box 56)
  - San Francisco Giants World Champions enamel pin, 2014 (Offsite-box 55)
  - Hillary Clinton Democratic National Convention signs, 2016 (Offsite-box 63)
    Two blue Hillary signs on cardboard poles from the Democratic National Convention 2016.
  - International Tennis Hall of Fame BJK Court framed dedication, 2016 (Offsite-box 66, Item 2)
  - Battle of the Sexes film paper fan, 2017 (Offsite-box 53)
    Paper fan promotional item for the Battle of the Sexes 2017 film. 2 fans included.
  - Ilana Kloss Jewish Sports Heritage Association Good Guy in Sports Award plaque, 2017 April 30 (Offsite-box 56)
  - Adidas Here to Create Change BJK tennis balls, 2018 (Offsite-box 53)
    3 cans of 3 tennis balls each created by Adidas as part of the Here to Create Change campaign with BJK. Tennis balls have text on them, reading, "You can't compete with the boys," "Women's sports aren't 'Real' sports," and "Why would women be paid the same as men?".
  - LA Dodgers hat signed by BJK and Ilana Kloss, 2018 (Offsite-box 53)
  - Clive Davis Pre-Grammy Gala invitation and case, 2019 February 9 (Offsite-box 54)
  - Murano pendant, undated (Offsite-box 54)
  - American flag on dowel, undated (Offsite-box 63)